<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Services on Annaamalai Ortho and Spine Center</title>
    <link>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/services/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Services on Annaamalai Ortho and Spine Center</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Arthritis Management</title>
      <link>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/arthritis-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/arthritis-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inflammation and degeneration in the joints leads to pain and this condition is called &lt;strong&gt;Arthritis&lt;/strong&gt;. Pain can be managed to a certain extent with medication and physiotherapy in the initial stages. Arthritis is the kind of condition that gets worse with time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back and Neck Pain Management</title>
      <link>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/back-and-neck-pain-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/back-and-neck-pain-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Back pain&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Neck Pain&lt;/strong&gt; are the most common aches that bring patients to Annamalai Ortho and Spine Center. When the pain is severe and has developed suddenly, it is considered acute. While &lt;a href=&#34;../chronic-pain-management&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chronic pain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; tends to last for weeks or even months together it is considered a chronic condition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bone and Spine Oncology</title>
      <link>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/bone-and-spine-oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/bone-and-spine-oncology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bone cancer can occur in any part of the body but the most common regions include the spine and pelvis. Most often the tumors are benign (non-aggressive), but the possibility of a non-cancerous tumor cannot be ignored. Spinal/ bone cancer is the growth of abnormal cells in the spinal cord or the bones.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chronic Pain Management</title>
      <link>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/chronic-pain-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/chronic-pain-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chronic pain&lt;/strong&gt; lasts for months together and is spread across different parts of the body. &lt;strong&gt;Pain relief&lt;/strong&gt; is fleeting. Unlike acute pain that arises suddenly due to a specific cause and goes away with treatment, chronic pain is persistent to such an extent that it interferes with simple daily-tasks/ day to day activities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fracture Management</title>
      <link>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/fracture-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/fracture-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A fracture refers to a broken bone and this could even be a small crack. The initial management of a fracture involves two important steps: realignment of the broken limb and then immobilizing it with the help of a splint. Splinting provides symptomatic pain relief and prevents further injury to the local soft tissues.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint Preservation and PRP Therapy</title>
      <link>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/joint-preservation-and-prp-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/joint-preservation-and-prp-therapy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Platelet rich plasma&lt;/strong&gt; therapy is commonly referred to as &amp;lsquo;PRP&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annamalai Ortho and Spine Center offers &lt;strong&gt;PRP Therapy&lt;/strong&gt;, an advanced non-operative out-patient procedure that can provide a permanent solution for conditions such as arthritis and ligament/tendon sprains and tears.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint Replacement</title>
      <link>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/joint-replacement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/joint-replacement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joint replacement&lt;/strong&gt; surgery at Annamalai Ortho and Spine Center is a routine procedure but it recommended only for people with &lt;strong&gt;chronic joint pain&lt;/strong&gt; when other non-surgical treatments have proved unsuccessful. The procedure helps relieve the pain completely and also improves joint mobility.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keyhole Surgery</title>
      <link>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/keyhole-surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/keyhole-surgery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Annamalai Ortho and Spine Center is fully equipped/ trained to perform a &lt;strong&gt;minimally invasive procedure&lt;/strong&gt; at the problem area (Spine/ joint). Minimally invasive procedure is commonly called a &lt;strong&gt;Keyhole Surgery&lt;/strong&gt; because the incision made is extremely small in comparison to traditional surgery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Osteoporosis</title>
      <link>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/osteoporosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/osteoporosis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About 200 million people are estimated to have osteoporosis throughout the world. &lt;strong&gt;Osteoporosis&lt;/strong&gt; occurs in both men and women, however &lt;strong&gt;osteoporosis in women&lt;/strong&gt; is more common - women are four times more likely to develop the disease than men.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prolapsed Disc</title>
      <link>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/prolapsed-disc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/prolapsed-disc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The spine is made up of several cylindrical bones called vertebrae and between each vertebra is a disc. These discs are made of a rubbery/jelly material that gives the spine its flexibility. The soft jelly-like centre of the disc, may sometimes leak out due to a weakness in the outer part of the disc. This is what is referred to as a herniated disc or prolapsed disc or protruded disc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sciatica Treatment</title>
      <link>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/sciatica-treatment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/sciatica-treatment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sciatica&lt;/strong&gt; is a collective term for a combination of symptoms such as &lt;strong&gt;leg pain&lt;/strong&gt;, tingling or numbness that travels down the low back via the sciatic nerve in the back of the leg. Sciatica can be caused by disc herniation compressing the spine nerve, spinal stenosis, degenerative disc disease, and spondylolisthesis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scoliosis and Kyphosis Correction</title>
      <link>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/scoliosis-and-kyphosis-correction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/scoliosis-and-kyphosis-correction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you fear that there is some structural problem with your spine, then an appointment with Dr. Vignesh Pushparaj is in order. Kyphosis and Scoliosis affect the structure of the spine. Scoliosis refers to an S-shaped or C-shaped spinal deformity that is noticeable when looking directly at the person.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spine Fracture Management</title>
      <link>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/spine-fracture-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/spine-fracture-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We at Annamalai Spine and Ortho Center understand how debilitating a spine fracture can be. Unlike a fracture in any other bone, a fracture in the spine can really put you out of action. From experiencing a nagging pain to not being able to stand or walk around t or even be paralyzed, the impact of a spinal injury or fracture can be quite dire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sports Medicine</title>
      <link>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/sports-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/sports-medicine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sports Medicine at Annamalai Ortho and Spince Center is focused on treating those who sustain injuries during sports related activities or during a workout. Sports medicine aims at helping the individual such that he/she recovers and returns to active life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X-Ray and Physiotherapy</title>
      <link>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/x-ray-and-physiotherapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annaamalaiorthospine.com/x-ray-and-physiotherapy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Through Physiotherapy Dr. Vignesh Pushparaj aims at restoring, maintaining, and maximizing a patient&amp;rsquo;s mobility after an injury or surgery or the onset of a medical condition that restricts their movement. It involves the care of our entire musculoskeletal system that includes the Bones, Muscles, Ligaments, Tendons, Joints and Connective tissue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
